[Music]
[音乐]
hello everybody and welcome to this
大家好，欢迎光临
session during this session we'll try
会议期间，我们将尝试
and talk about how to make your web apps
并讨论如何制作您的网络应用
a bit more efficient and how to
更有效率，以及如何
introduce a bit of reactive into your
在你的身上引入一些反应性
apps even if you're not really into it
应用程序，即使您不是很喜欢它
but first we always like to ask a few
但首先，我们总是喜欢问几个
questions to know a bit more about you
要进一步了解您的问题
so raise your hand if you're using
因此，如果您正在使用，请举手
spring boot - one currently infraction
弹簧靴-当前违规
we don't see anything yeah quite a lot
我们什么也没看到
actually it was still on spring boot one
实际上它仍然在 spring boot 上
five oh yeah
五哦是的
it's end-of-life is August right so just
生命的尽头是八月，所以
so you know just so you know and we also
所以你知道，所以你知道，我们也
want to know if you've those of you
想知道你是否拥有那些
who've never heard of reactive
从来没有听说过反应
programming before they don't know what
在他们不知道之前编程
it is you've heard of it if you're never
如果你从没听说过，那是你听说过的
used it at all in an application oh yeah
完全在应用程序中使用过
that too good okay okay that's that's
太好了，好吧，那是
good we'll try and bring a different
好，我们会尝试带来不同的
perspective to it so we've been spending
透视它，所以我们一直在花钱
quite a lot of time for the past three
过去三个时间很多
years to tell you about those new
年告诉你这些新东西
options you have when you're building a
建立房屋时的选择
web application with spring boot so as
带有Spring Boot的Web应用程序
you probably know as of spring boot -
您可能从Spring Boot开始就知道-
there is a new option using spring web
使用spring web有一个新选项
flux and the reactive stack so these are
通量和电抗堆，所以它们是
the two choices that you you have to
您必须选择的两个选择
make now and the purpose of this talk we
现在就做和本次演讲的目的
realize that by explaining those two
通过解释这两个来意识到
choices and basically that were two
选择，基本上是两个
options we were like really focusing
我们真正专注的选择
with either you do this or you do that
要么你做这个，要么你做那个
and actually we're going to give you as
实际上，我们将为您提供
much of options as possible and there's
尽可能多的选择，并且
actually a third options that we are
实际上是我们的第三个选择
going to show you in demos today yeah
今天要在演示中向您展示
and this new option is basically as
这个新选项基本上是
Brian mentioned to use your existing
Brian提到要使用您现有的
spring MVC based application and use
基于Spring MVC的应用程序和使用
some of the reactive which some of the
一些反应性的一些
reactive features on the back end so for
后端的反应功能，因此
that we have a small example that we
我们有一个小例子
want to show
想展示
yeah so you probably know about star
是的，所以您可能了解星级
spring that IO so the best way to boost
提升IO的效率
up your screen with application on the
屏幕上的应用程序
Internet
互联网
so when you fill the form and you click
因此，当您填写表格并单击
on it you're getting a project back from
关于它，您正在从
that but what we do is we collect the
那是我们要做的是收集
project request so what you asked as a
项目要求，所以您要求
project and we put that in an index
项目，并将其放入索引中
anonymized so that we know what the
匿名，以便我们知道
spring community is busy with what you'd
春季社区忙于您的工作
like to do we see the trends so it's
我们想看到趋势，所以
giving us and nice data points to figure
给我们和不错的数据点来图
out when in which area we should invest
指出我们应该在哪个领域进行投资
and so on so it's not only true for the
等等，不仅对于
web interface same thing for IDs and
Web界面对ID和
command line curled etc because it's all
命令行卷曲等，因为这一切
going to the same service in the end so
最后要去同样的服务
this is super useful for us and we're
这对我们超级有用，我们
not using the real star swing the Rio
不使用真正的明星摇摆里约
instance today but we'll actually use
今天的实例，但我们实际上会使用
something that resembles what we get but
类似于我们得到的东西，但是
this time what we also do in real life
这次我们在现实生活中也做
is that we're looking at that index
是我们正在查看该索引
through a dashboard and trying to figure
通过仪表板并试图找出
out trends and wondering what's going on
了解趋势，想知道发生了什么事
and so on so now in this example so
依此类推，现在在这个例子中
we're we from now on we that's not
从现在开始我们就是我们
representing reality so in this example
代表现实，所以在这个例子中
what we'll do is we'll work on a
我们要做的是
dashboard application that does just
仪表板应用程序
that plus looking at so the metadata the
加上看着元数据
index so all the queries that were
索引，以便所有的查询
stored plus two other sources of data
存储以及另外两个数据源
one is doing IP lookup to figure out so
一个正在做IP查找来找出这样
we'd like to know if someone is abusing
我们想知道是否有人在滥用
the service like plugging a CI and doing
该服务就像插入CI并执行
a lot of creations so we want to do
很多创意，所以我们想做
reverse lookup to see what's going on
反向查找以查看发生了什么
and as well another source of data which
以及另一个数据来源
would be another service looking at
将会是另一项服务
events calendar events what what
事件日历事件什么
happened at one point in time to try and
发生在某一时间尝试
correlate things in case of like various
在各种情况下关联事物
events and that's it imagine phone for
事件，那就是想象电话
this sample dashboard application that
该示例仪表板应用程序
those three services you can you don't
这三项服务，您无法做到
all them so they had they have an epi
所有的人，所以他们有一个Epi
you have to comply with they potentially
您必须潜在地遵守他们
are potentially not a new deployment
可能不是新的部署
environment so they are removed and
环境，以便将它们删除并
there are challenges as basically trying
基本上是尝试的挑战
to aggregate that data to build a death
汇总数据以造成死亡
toll UI that's what we are going to
收费用户界面，这就是我们要做的
focus on if you miss hopefully that's
专注于如果您希望错过那是
not going to happen but if you miss one
不会发生，但是如果你想念一个
of those demos or something that's not
这些演示或其他
clear and you want to get it back too
清除，您也想找回它
we will share at the end of the
我们将在最后分享
presentation a link to a get up repo
演示指向起床仓库的链接
where you can download the code so
您可以在此处下载代码，以便
there's basically two application two
基本上有两个应用程序二
applications there's one that's
应用程序是一个
simulating those three services
模拟这三个服务
generating random data and there's one
生成随机数据，有一个
which represents the dashboard
代表仪表板
application which startup those two apps
启动这两个应用程序的应用程序
on your laptop you can basically
在笔记本电脑上，您基本上可以
replicate what we are doing here yeah
复制我们在这里做什么
and on that repository every step of the
并且在该存储库中，
demo is a separate commit with like
演示是一个单独的提交，就像
messages and so on so you can really
消息等，这样您就可以真正
follow by looking at the roster in case
通过查看名单以防万一
you missed it you missed something shows
你错过了你错过了一些节目
it just to put outside a bit of the
它只是把一点点
mystery this is the kind of data that we
神秘，这是我们所需要的数据
get from one of the endpoints so the it
从端点之一获得
everything is so the back end is running
一切都很好，所以后端正在运行
on 8081
在8081
there's a statistics end point where you
有一个统计终点
can we can get trends about project
我们可以得到有关项目的趋势吗
generations we also have a services
几代人我们也有服务
called events which gives you random
所谓的事件，它给你随机
events in this case it's not really
在这种情况下不是真的
random not sure slack was down but yeah
随机不确定松弛是否下降，但是
whatever and there's also a services
随便什么，还有服务
that gives you the top IPs and I was
这为您提供了顶级IP，而我当时
talking we were talking to you about the
谈论我们正在和您谈论
fact that the service API is fixed so
服务API是固定的事实，因此
you basically I have a first call where
你基本上我有第一个电话
you get the top IPS but you we don't
您获得了最高的IPS，但您却没有
want to show that we want to show the
想要表明我们想要显示
real name so we need to call something
真实姓名，所以我们需要打个电话
that the reversal cap and we can
逆转上限，我们可以
unfortunately only call that service one
不幸的是，只叫那个服务一个
IP at a time right so let's have a look
一次正确的IP，让我们来看一下
to our application looks like this at
我们的应用程序看起来像这样
the moment and it's a regular spring MVC
此刻，这是常规的春季MVC
application calling that that back-end
应用程序调用该后端
on on port 8080 80 81
在端口8080 80 81上
so very quickly we have this client
很快我们有了这个客户
using the rest and play it and basically
用剩下的玩，基本上
calling those three services right we
我们称这三项服务为正确
were just showing you and then there is
只是向你展示，然后有
some more involved API here well yeah so
这里有更多涉及的API是的，所以
we're we're as you can guess we're
我们是我们，正如您所猜到的
getting the generation statistics we're
得到我们的世代统计
getting the the top the events the top
把事件放在第一位
IPS and so on we're getting that I can
IPS等，我们可以
use sequential manner and we're wrapping
使用顺序方式，我们包装
all that in a static container and
所有这些都放在静态容器中，
that's a an object that will give to the
这是一个对象，将给予
template to the to the model so that we
模板的模型，以便我们
can render the page that you've seen on
可以呈现您看到过的页面
the dashboard application with a graph
带有图表的仪表板应用程序
and everything gathered in one place so
一切都聚集在一个地方
we're gathering all the data from
我们正在收集来自的所有数据
several sources shoving that into a
有几个消息来源将其推论为
static container object and rendering so
静态容器对象并进行渲染
then the container is basically used in
那么该容器基本上用于
this controller where I basically build
我基本上在这里构建的控制器
a model and basically passing that to a
模型，并将其基本上传递给
time leaf tiny template I believe yeah
我相信时间叶小模板
which is rendering the page so so far
到目前为止，这一直在渲染页面
it's a pretty usual spring MVC
这是一个非常平常的春季MVC
application using extreme spring boots
使用极端弹簧靴的应用
nothing special to it and we will run
没什么特别的，我们将运行
into some problems and we'd like to see
遇到一些问题，我们希望看到
how we can solve those for our
我们如何为我们解决这些问题
application so one of the problems that
应用程序的问题之一
we have at the moment was the stat
我们目前的状态是
service is it's basically in a blocking
服务是它基本上处于阻塞状态
mode right so those three API calls
模式正确，因此这三个API调用
potentially you don't you need you don't
可能你不需要，你不需要
need to call them one by one you need
需要一一称呼他们
all of all the data to build a container
所有的数据来建立一个容器
but there is actually no requirement to
但实际上并不需要
first get the stats then events then to
首先获取统计信息，然后获取事件，然后
top IPs
顶级IP
yet in the in the current infrastructure
在目前的基础架构中
using the rest template these are
使用其余模板，这些是
actually blocking the threat and we want
实际上阻​​止了威胁，我们想要
to show you how you can basically use an
向您展示如何基本使用
alternative solution as basically
基本上是替代解决方案
managing the threat for yourself doing
自己处理威胁
drawings and timeouts and all that mess
图纸和超时以及所有混乱情况
you don't want to do that
你不想那样做
if you've done that you know it's it's
如果您已经知道那是
quite plentiful so the third option we
非常丰富，所以第三种选择
were talking about is basically to add
基本上是要添加
some of the reactive stuff in your
您的一些反应性物质
existing app and the way to do that is
现有应用程序的方式是
to add a starter so when you add the
添加启动器，所以当您添加
Springwood starter reactive Web Start
Springwood启动器反应式Web Start
webparts what you get is the nest the
webparts你得到的是巢
you card infrastructure to start a web
您将基础架构建立网络
flex application so you get the server
flex应用程序，以便您获取服务器
parts and the web client parts as well
部件和Web客户端部件
but when you have both web and web flux
但是当您同时拥有网络和网络流量时
starters on the classpath what we do is
类路径上的入门者，我们要做的是
that we expect you to be in a case where
我们希望您能在以下情况下
you have a spring MVC application and
您有一个Spring MVC应用程序，
you'd like to use the web client so
您想使用网络客户端
that's why when you have both on the
这就是为什么当您同时在
classpath it's still gonna be an MVC
classpath仍然会是MVC
application because MVC supports as well
应用程序，因为MVC也支持
parts of the the reactive story on
反应性故事的一部分
endpoints so this is where you are
端点，所以这就是你所在的地方
Springs spring MVC application still but
Springs Spring MVC应用仍然
we Auto configure a few things around
我们会自动配置一些东西
the reactive story including the web
反应性的故事，包括网络
client so that's where we can switch our
客户，这是我们可以切换我们的地方
rest and plate
休息和盘子
builder by a web client so just like
由网络客户端构建，就像
just like we do for restaurant plate
就像我们为餐厅拼盘一样
builder which is a spring boot class in
生成器，它是Spring Boot中的类
spring boot we are Auto configuring a
春季启动我们正在自动配置
builder for you with all the preferences
具有所有偏好的建筑商
and opinions you've expressed so far so
到目前为止你表达的观点
including jackson series asian ups and
包括杰克逊系列亚洲人ups和
options and so on including customizers
选项等，包括定制器
and and the usual so once you get that
和通常的，所以一旦你得到
you can build your own web client
您可以建立自己的网络客户端
instance and you can translate them the
实例，您可以翻译它们
API
API
yeah the API is a bit different but yet
是的，API有点不同，但是
it was an opportunity for the team to
这是团队的机会
actually review what we did with the
实际回顾我们对
rest and plate but the main the main
休息和板块，但主要的主要
change with this API is that using the
此API的变化是使用
web client does not actually return you
网络客户端实际上并没有返回您
the data but it returns a publisher to
数据，但它将发布者返回给
the data so the publisher is fully lazy
数据，因此发布者完全懒惰
so nothing happens to it until you
所以直到你什么都没有发生
subscribe you're actually calling and
订阅您实际上正在呼叫并
asking for the data so right now we're
要求数据，所以现在我们
describing when you when you return
描述您何时返回
omona or flux you're describing some
omona或助焊剂，您正在描述一些
kind of pipeline and nothing happens
那种管道，什么也没发生
until something asks for for data other
直到某些东西要求其他数据
than that the API is pretty
比那个API还漂亮
straightforward on the web client I
在Web客户端上简单易懂
really like it
真喜欢它
and it allows you to do what what you'd
它可以让你做自己想做的事
expect except you can translate single
期望，除了你可以翻译单
element to Munoz and multiple elements
Munoz和多个元素的元素
to fluxes that's pretty much it all
助焊剂就差不多了
right so let's not do everything because
对，所以我们不做任何事情，因为
it's boring let me check out that okay
很无聊，让我检查一下
so once you have that we have to take
所以一旦你有，我们必须采取
care of the other layer so instead of
照顾另一层，所以而不是
getting directly the generation
直接获得一代
statistics we are provided with a mono
统计信息我们提供了一个单声道
or flux so the as a first type what we
或通量，所以作为第一种类型，我们
can do is just calling block which is a
可以做的就是调用block
very bad idea if you've got a fully
如果您有足够的能力，这是一个非常糟糕的主意
reactive application but we're an MVC
反应性应用程序，但我们是MVC
and it's as a first step it's perfectly
这是第一步，非常完美
fine it's just the equivalent of what we
很好，这相当于我们的
did actually with rest in place so with
实际上在适当的地方休息了
this we kind of have the perfect
这是我们的完美
equivalent of what we had with Wes
相当于我们对Wes的了解
template blocking and getting things
模板阻止和获取东西
sequentially but we'd like to do a bit
按顺序，但我们想做一点
more and try and improve things with
更多，并尝试改善
this because we're wet with wet plan we
这是因为我们被湿润的计划弄湿了
can we can do actually more so one step
我们可以做更多的事情吗？
to improve that is rather than basically
改善那不是根本
blocking on each publisher which isn't
阻止每个不是的发布者
doesn't give you anything really is to
真的没有给你任何东西
try to compose the data one layer up and
尝试将数据组成一层
this better
这个更好
this method is basically doing some
这种方法基本上是在做一些
composition with free calls to freeze
免费打电话冻结的构图
free services and from one particular
免费服务，来自一个特定的
one whenever a new element is received
每当收到一个新元素时
calling yet another one to do the
叫另一个人去做
reverse lookup so the idea now is to
反向查找，所以现在的想法是
stop blocking from each of those
停止阻止每个人
elements keep the publisher and use
元素保持发布者的使用
additional operators of project reactor
项目反应堆的其他运营商
to improve the composition yeah we want
改善成分，是的，我们想要
to do as much as possible in parallel
尽可能并行
and we want to use our resources
我们想利用我们的资源
efficiently so this is how instead of
有效地，所以这是代替
blocking at every every step we want to
阻挡我们想要的每一步
compose and get all the Manos all those
组成并获得所有的Manos
future values which are not futures it's
不是期货的未来价值
it's really amazing so getting all those
真的很棒，所以得到所有这些
and zipping them into the same container
并将它们压缩到同一容器中
so that everything is triggered and
这样就触发了一切
happen
发生
at the same time in parallel so once we
同时并行，所以一旦我们
once we have all those three Manos then
一旦我们拥有了所有这三个马诺斯
we can compose them so here Stefan is a
我们可以组成它们，所以斯特凡是一个
calling collect collect list this is
呼叫收集收集列表，这是
this is because we don't want to flux we
这是因为我们不想改变我们
don't want to get the elements one by
不想让元素一个
one we want to get the full list because
我们想要获得完整列表，因为
that's what we need to to render the
这就是我们需要渲染的
whole page so collect list is just
整个页面，所以收集列表只是
giving you instead of giving you
给你而不是给你
elements one by one it's giving you a
元素一一给你
mana of the list of everything so for
一切清单的法力值
the top clients really we would the
真正的顶级客户
pipeline what it does is it it's first
管道它是做什么的，这是第一个
calling that that top IP service that
调用那个最重要的IP服务
will give you 10 IPS and and then we
会给您10 IPS，然后我们
need to transform the them that further
需要进一步改造它们
in that case we are actually interested
在这种情况下，我们实际上很感兴趣
by doing something as soon as we can so
尽快做些事情
we don't want to build a full list of
我们不想建立完整的清单
the top IPs and once we have connected
顶级IP，一旦我们建立连接
that and we basically get a list as a
那我们基本上得到一个列表作为
mono start actually issuing additional
单声道开始实际发行额外
requests we want to do that right away
请求我们想要立即做到
so to do that I'm actually going to use
为此，我实际上将要使用
this code initially which which returns
此代码最初返回
a flux of IPs and for each of them so
大量的IP，对于每个IP都是如此
whenever I get a new element I want to
每当我得到一个新元素时
issue a call to the lookup client so in
向查找客户端发出呼叫，因此
that sense we're trying to make some
从某种意义上说，我们正在努力做出一些
things happen in parallel some other
事情并行发生
other things happen in parallel but
其他事情并行发生，但是
inside some parts of it so trying and
里面的某些部分，所以尝试和
expressing that in an imperative manner
势在必行
it's super hard you need like concurrent
您需要像并发这样的超级困难
programming techniques and and building
编程技术与建设
blocks it's it's really hard if you do
阻止，这真的很难
that in a declarative manner you have to
以声明的方式，你必须
understand a bit the operators but it's
有点了解运营商，但这是
kind of visualizing a pipeline in
一种可视化的管道
multiple pipelines and if you've played
多个管道，如果您玩过
merio a lot like I did when I was a kid
像我小时候一样很开心
it's a kind of visual so it's a bit like
这是一种视觉效果，所以有点像
that you plug things in with the with
你用插入东西
each other and and it works clicks so
彼此，它的工作点击
this is basically telling I want I want
这基本上是在告诉我想要
a flux of those IP of those descriptors
这些描述符的那些IP的变化
basically and whenever you get a new
基本上，只要有新东西
entry I just call that basically get the
我只是称该条目为基本
the object as a lambda parameter then
然后将该对象作为lambda参数
change it to something else and that
将其更改为其他内容
basically returns you a flux of that
基本上会为您带来
thing mapped in the end I'm also only
最终映射的东西我也是
interested by the list so I can actually
感兴趣的列表，所以我实际上
on that method I've created I can invoke
在我创建的方法上，我可以调用
collect this together so yeah here we've
一起收集这些，是的，我们在这里
got everything we need
得到了我们需要的一切
and we again we need to zip yeah so we
我们再次需要拉开拉链，所以我们
need basically needs to tell reactor
需要基本上需要告诉反应堆
here are the three things that I have I
这是我拥有的三件事
don't care how but just get them for me
不管如何，只为我买
and once you have them call me back and
一旦有他们给我打电话，
I'll run some additional business logic
我将运行一些其他业务逻辑
and there's an operator as Brad
还有一个操作员，如Brad
mentioned called zip that does that
提到称为zip的功能
where you can specify a bunch of
您可以在其中指定一堆
publishers
出版商
so that's generation stats events n top
这就是世代统计事件
clients and there is a map method that
客户，并且有一个map方法
basically gives you a callback whenever
基本上在任何时候都会给您回调
the data is available yeah so inside
数据是可用的，所以里面
that topple you'll get all the types
翻倒，您将获得所有类型
that you've that you've specified before
您之前指定的
so inside the the first the t1 and
所以在第一个t1里面
topple you'll get the stats and the
翻倒，您将获得统计数据和
second one you get the events and so on
第二个得到事件，依此类推
so from there we can reuse our builder
所以从那里我们可以重用我们的构建器
and just get our aim owner of our
并得到我们的目标所有者
container in the end so it took a couple
容器到底，所以花了几个
of steps but we've got a we've got a
的步骤，但我们有一个
builder and we'll get a mono from it in
生成器，我们将从中获取单声道
the end so basically what you get you
最终，基本上你得到了什么
get an object if you pass three
如果通过三则得到一个物体
publishers you get a tapper back with
发布商，您可以从中获得丝锥
three accessors if false you get false
三个访问器，如果为假，则为假
you know you get yeah there's a limit do
你知道你有限制
you know the limit because I always
你知道极限，因为我一直
forget there's no there are a few
忘了没有
implementations with the explicit
显式实现
arguments and then there's a that's a
参数，然后有一个是
devourer bargain right right right okay
吞噬者讨价还价正确正确正确
oh there we go reasons so now I can
哦，我们走了，所以现在我可以
basically return that stuff and I don't
基本上归还那些东西，我不
need that old code and we don't use that
需要旧的代码，我们不使用它
anymore and ultimately what that code
不再是那个代码了
which we will return is a publisher of
我们将返回的是
the container right so you've pushed the
正确的容器，所以您已将
logic one day one day your app and still
逻辑一天一天您的应用仍然
at that point nothing happens if you
那时，如果您没有任何反应
just get the mono and you if you don't
只是得到单声道，如果你不这样做
do anything on it
做任何事情
then nothing happens so let's make sure
那么什么也没发生，所以让我们确保
it does so here we're calling block
这样做，所以我们在这里调用块
because our view rendering technology
因为我们的视图渲染技术
doesn't support reactive rendering so
不支持反应性渲染，因此
just doing that will trigger and
只是这样做会触发
subscribe and render everything at once
一次订阅并呈现所有内容
so here we're way more efficient because
所以在这里我们效率更高，因为
everything happens in parallel we're not
一切并行发生，我们不是
paying the cost of the latency multiple
付出倍数的等待时间
times so we're in a better situation but
时代，所以我们处在更好的状态，但是
still problem can happen and we have one
问题仍然可能发生，我们有一个
one small thing here so an opportunity
这里有一件小事，是一个机会
to show you how you can easily test that
向您展示如何轻松测试
stuff so that's an MC test for the
东西，所以这是MC测试
controller I have a test here where I'm
控制器，我在这里进行测试
basically mocking the status service and
基本上嘲笑身份服务
validate the content so it used it used
验证内容，以便使用它
to return the container now it returns a
现在返回容器
mono of container so I need to adapt
容器的单声道，所以我需要适应
that called the reading there we go so
那叫阅读，我们去了
so far so good
到现在为止还挺好
except now let's make sure something
除了现在，让我们确保一些事情
weird happens yeah so on the back end we
怪异的发生是的，所以在后端我们
have a latency service that's
有一个延迟服务
implemented as a custom actuator
实现为自定义执行器
endpoint so if you're interested by that
终点，所以如果您对此感兴趣
you can check out the code and the
您可以检查代码和
latency end point basically slows down
延迟终点基本上会减慢
and a ratio of requests just for the
和仅用于
purpose of the demonstration between 200
200之间的示范目的
milliseconds and 8,000 milliseconds
毫秒和8,000毫秒
right right now we can see the ratio and
现在我们可以看到比率和
where if you can read that from the back
在哪里可以从背面阅读
the ratio is at zero but you would have
该比率为零，但您将拥有
saw 0% and what I'm going to do is I'm
看到0％，我要做的就是
going to change it basically to an
基本上将其更改为
update on the back end to change it to
在后端更新以将其更改为
80% yeah basically what we're trying to
80％是的，基本上我们正在尝试
do is something that should resonate if
做的事应该引起共鸣
you ever had to call a service that you
你曾经不得不打电话给你的服务
don't that's not really under your
难道那不是真的在你的下
control and sometimes the latency is
控制，有时等待时间是
just awful and it can bring your whole
简直糟透了，它可以带给您全部
system down if you don't pay attention
如果不注意，则系统崩溃
to it so this is basically that use case
为此，这基本上是用例
that we're trying to solve
我们试图解决的
Wow it's a bit slow now it really is so
哇，现在有点慢了，真的是如此
I'm I remember we also had some kind of
我记得我们也有某种
indicator for the remote service so
远程服务指示器
maybe you have a look to it oh so that's
也许你看看它哦，那是
what you get by default whispering good
你默认得到的耳语好
- you don't get any details
-您没有任何详细信息
you basically have to opt-in to get more
您基本上必须选择加入才能获得更多
details so let me actually do that
细节，所以让我实际去做
quickly so we like to see the the
快速，所以我们希望看到
details of the health endpoint to see if
运行状况端点的详细信息以查看是否
we get more things than just up and in
我们得到的不仅仅是刚起步的东西
our case I believe we've built a
我们的情况，我相信我们已经建立了一个
specific health indicator - to know
具体的健康指标-要知道
about the reverse lookup service to see
有关反向查找服务的信息
if it's up so basically what the
如果是这样，基本上
indicator what that indicator is doing
指示指标在做什么
is just sending your query to that
只是向您发送查询
service seeing if everything works out
服务看是否一切正常
and then saying up or down in our case
然后就我们的情况说上下
it's still up so it doesn't say much oh
还在，所以没多说哦
by the way as you notice that the
顺便说一句，您注意到
application restarted automatically have
应用程序自动重启有
you noticed Doria a good question who
你注意到多里亚一个好问题是谁
doesn't know what Springwood death tools
不知道什么是Springwood死亡工具
is I've all right quite a few ok all
我没事吧好吗
right
对
so spring boot dev tools is an optional
所以Spring Boot开发工具是可选的
module you can add to your project what
您可以在项目中添加什么模块
it does basically it's it's going to
基本上，这是要
monitor your class path going to
监控您的上课路径
monitoring project files it will start
监视将启动的项目文件
your application in development in a
您在开发中的应用
certain way so that if you change a file
某种方式，以便您更改文件
it will notice that and restart the
它会注意到并重新启动
application it will restart the VM
应用程序，它将重新启动VM
process because it couldn't but it will
过程，因为它不能，但是会
restart the application context in an
重新启动应用程序上下文
efficient manner
有效的方式
which basically allows you to do changes
基本上可以让您进行更改
to a running application and get them
到正在运行的应用程序并获取它们
updated automatically so that's one
自动更新，所以这是一个
thing it does the other thing it does is
它做的另一件事是
it also implements a very very basic
它也实现了非常非常基本的
live reload server so that's the the
实时重新加载服务器，因此
plug-in I've added to my browser over
我已将浏览器插件添加到浏览器中
there for we can see it I don't even see
在那里，我们可以看到它，我什至看不到
my mouse there we go
我的鼠标在那里
so when you when you have such an
所以当你有这样一个
application running with dev tools you
使用开发工具运行的应用程序
can connect your browser to the spring
可以将浏览器连接到弹簧
bootie application and once once the
靴子应用程序，一旦
application has restarted it can request
应用程序已重新启动，可以请求
a browser to refresh yeah depending on
浏览器刷新是的，取决于
the changes you do if it's code related
与代码相关的更改
it will restart the context if it's just
如果只是，它将重新启动上下文
a static file it'll just trigger the
一个静态文件，它将触发
library load on your browser so you
库加载到浏览器中，因此您
don't have to do it manually and you
不必手动进行，您
won't restart anything in your app
不会重新启动您应用中的任何内容
so in the idea that there's a there's a
所以有一个想法
nice integration for it so for instance
很好的集成，例如
in IntelliJ IDE they have this on frame
在IntelliJ IDE中，它们在框架上
deactivation option where you can ask it
您可以在哪里询问停用选项
to update classes and resources so
更新类和资源，以便
basically incrementally compiled you
基本上增量编译你
project a copy copy properties files
投影副本复制属性文件
that have changed so the the the
已经改变了，所以
experience that you do a bunch of
经历你做一堆
changes then you switch to the browser
更改，然后切换到浏览器
typically if you're running a web app so
通常，如果您正在运行网络应用程序，那么
you're basically losing the focus on the
您基本上失去了对
IntelliJ window and that will trigger an
IntelliJ窗口，这将触发
incremental computation which will
增量计算
trigger a dev tools etc so definitely if
一定会触发开发工具等
you're working on stream wheel
你在流轮上工作
applications and you don't have that
应用程序，而您没有
dependency you're really missing out
依赖，你真的错过了
because we're really putting a lot of
因为我们真的投入了很多
stuff in there to make sure that you get
那里的东西，以确保你得到
a nice development experience and that
很好的开发经验，
you don't have to wait for nothing so
您不必等待任何事情，因此
the application is still slow though so
应用程序仍然很慢，尽管如此
what what should we do the earth
我们该怎么办地球
educator says happen the problem is if
教育家说​​发生的问题是
the service would be like down when a
当一个
resource is down basically the the
资源基本上下降了
indicators they're useful because you
指示符之所以有用，是因为您
know something's broken but here it's
知道有些东西坏了，但这是
not broken in the sense that it doesn't
没有被打破的意义
work it's broken sense that your
工作是一种破碎的感觉
customers unhappy and this is the
客户不满意，这就是
difference between like checking the
喜欢检查之间的区别
health of your application and and
您的应用程序的运行状况，以及
checking like the current status and the
检查像当前状态和
performance and how things are running
性能以及运行方式
currently and so that's the difference
目前，这就是区别
between what we do with actuator in
我们在执行器之间
spring moon and what we call
春月和我们所说的
observability and those are like you
可观察性，那些就像你
should have both and not one or the
应该同时拥有而不是其中之一
other because it's it's it's it's really
其他，因为它是它是真的
working on at different levels so with
在不同层次上工作
spring with two there's a new project
有两个的春天有一个新项目
that we've integrated because if you've
我们已经整合，因为如果您已经
been using metrics with spring one one
一开始就使用指标
five when the dot X you know that we
五点X时，您知道我们
have we have an API for that that we've
我们是否有一个针对我们的API
switch over a new project called macro
切换一个名为宏的新项目
meter so one question one more time
计，再问一个问题
sorry who knows about micro meter
抱歉，谁知道千分尺
okay turn that's that's a good transfer
好吧，那是一个很好的转移
fair amount people so the tagline of
相当多的人，所以的口号是
micro meter for those who don't know
那些不知道的人用的千分尺
about it it's they said the
关于它，他们说
like SLE for Jay but for matrix so they
像杰伊（Jay）的SLE，但矩阵（M矩阵）的SLE
have a bass API that you can use that's
有一个低音API，您可以使用
independent of any monitoring system or
独立于任何监视系统或
you can define matrix and operate on
您可以定义矩阵并对其进行操作
them like incrementing or decrementing
他们喜欢递增或递减
values adding meta information to to the
将元信息添加到
metric etc and from each monitoring
指标等，以及每次监控
system that micrometre supports and
微米支持的系统
there's a lot of them they will make
他们会做很多
sure they will do the heavy lifting for
确保他们会为
you so they will basically translate to
你，所以他们基本上会翻译成
the to the naming system of the
的命名系统
monitoring system they will publish the
监控系统，他们将发布
metric metrics to the monitoring system
监控系统的度量标准
it's a job the problem with metrics is
这是一项工作，指标的问题是
that if you want to have metrics you
如果您想拥有指标，
have to stick sneak into all the
必须潜入所有
libraries and everything you use to add
库以及用于添加的所有内容
those metrics and create them at some
这些指标并在某些时候创建它们
point
点
the good news is this is already done
好消息是这已经完成了
with with actuator
带执行器
we're already instrumented a lot of a
我们已经进行了很多测试
lot of things in the spring an ecosystem
春天的很多事情生态系统
so just having that will create a lot of
因此，拥有它会创造很多
metrics that you can look into and this
您可以研究的指标
is part of the spring boots report that
是 spring boot 报告的一部分
we're working on so this is a this is
我们正在努力，所以这是一个
already done and of course you can you
已经完成了，当然可以
can add your your your own and there are
可以添加您自己的，有
also other third-party projects not
还有其他第三方项目
related to spring at all that that I've
与春天有关的一切
picked up micro meter because micro
拿起微米，因为微
meter is not I mean specific it's not
米不是我的意思是不是
specific to spring so you can use it
特定于弹簧，因此您可以使用它
without spring if you wanted to and so
如果想要的话，没有春天
there are there are a bunch of projects
有很多项目
that have integrated that so if you're
已经集成了，所以如果你是
building if you're building with a
如果您使用的是建筑
system that uses micro meter like a
使用微米计的系统
spring boot app all those metrics will
春季启动应用程序所有这些指标将
be available to you as well so - if you
也可以使用-如果您
if you just add the actuator you'll get
如果您只添加执行器，您将获得
the in-memory metric endpoint which is
内存中指标端点是
not very useful it's just to make sure I
不是很有用，只是要确保我
mean to see what you have in the system
意味着要查看系统中的内容
but it's it's not pushing data anywhere
但这不是在任何地方推送数据
so for the purpose of the demo today we
因此，为了今天的演示，我们
are going to use primitives so once
将使用原语，所以一旦
you've chosen a money a monitoring
您选择了监控货币
system you need to add a registry
系统，您需要添加注册表
implementation on your class pass which
在您的课程通行证上实现
will do the translation I was talking
会做我在说的翻译
about
关于
so back to what we're trying to achieve
回到我们试图实现的目标
right now is that we know that
现在是我们知道
something's not working properly in our
我们的某些东西无法正常工作
system we're calling several remote
系统我们称几个远程
services we don't know which is behaving
我们不知道哪些服务正在表现
we don't know when really so it's really
我们不知道何时才是真的
hard to see what's going on so that's
很难看发生了什么事，那是
what we're trying to do we're trying to
我们正在尝试做的是
build metrics create them and we want to
建立指标来创建它们，我们希望
look at something a picture that tells
看一张图片，讲述
us where the problem is really and
我们真正的问题所在，
because a monitoring system may have
因为监控系统可能有
information about plenty of different
有关大量不同的信息
applications we want to make sure that
我们要确保的应用程序
the things the metrics that we are going
事物是我们要衡量的指标
to emit are tagged with something that
发出带有某些东西的标签
helped us isolate isolate them so the
帮助我们隔离了他们，因此
matrix as you'll see in a minute they
稍后您将看到矩阵
they have a concept of tags so you can
他们有标签的概念，因此您可以
add an arbitrary number of label to them
给他们添加任意数量的标签
if you if you want so you can for
如果您愿意，可以
instance add an application tag which
实例添加一个应用标签
has a given value and it will allow it
具有给定的值，它将允许它
will allow you in a monitoring system
将允许您使用监视系统
itself to say give me all the metrics
本身就是说给我所有指标
whose application tag as that value and
其应用程序标记为该值，以及
then you'll get only the matrix for that
那么您将只获得该矩阵
application typically you'd say
您通常会说的应用程序
application name and maybe the the
应用程序名称，也许
instance number and maybe the region if
实例号，如果可能的话
it's deployed on a cloud on a cloud
它部署在云上
environment stuff like that so there are
这样的环境的东西，所以有
tags that you can add on a per
您可以在每个标签上添加的标签
application basis and then there are
应用基础，然后有
tags that are created on the fly for the
即时为创建的标签
metric itself like for an HTTP request
指标本身，例如HTTP请求
the tags would be about the path the
标签将关于路径
status and so on and the metric itself
状态等指标本身
would be like the timing the time it
就像计时的时间一样
took to to process the requests most
最需要处理的请求
monitoring system are push based so when
监控系统是基于推送的，所以当
you when you add a registry for a
您在添加注册表时
monitoring system implementation you
监控系统实施情况
usually have to provide your API token
通常必须提供您的API令牌
and a destination and basically the
和目的地，基本上
implementation we start pushing metrics
实施中，我们开始推动指标
to the monitoring system primitives is a
监视系统原语是
bit different because it's it scraps
有点不同，因为它报废
data so it's basically expecting your
数据，因此基本上是在期待您的
application to expose an endpoint
公开端点的应用程序
somewhere with the primitives format and
具有原始格式的地方
depending on configuration as you can
取决于您的配置
see here it will basically call the
看到这里基本上会调用
application every 10 seconds 15 seconds
每10秒15秒
20 seconds
20秒
and update the state of the application
并更新应用程序的状态
for this one we have a job called spring
为此，我们有一份工作叫做春季
that every five seconds
每五秒钟
calls both our application sort of the
既调用我们的应用程序
back end and the dashboard so if I start
后端和仪表板，所以如果我开始
primitives on the command line it's
命令行上的原语是
reading for that Yemen file and it will
阅读也门文件，它将
just use that by default but there are
只是默认使用它，但是有
problems right now because it's trying
现在的问题，因为它正在尝试
to pull data from our applications and
从我们的应用程序中提取数据
our applications are not responding
我们的应用程序没有响应
properly this is because we have
正确的，这是因为我们有
security on the classpath and by default
在类路径上的安全性，默认情况下
it's protecting everything so you have
它保护着一切，所以你有
to configure application accordingly
相应地配置应用程序
so here in our case because we're not
所以在这里，因为我们不是
separating the the admin parts from the
将管理部分与
public parts this is everything
公共部分，这就是一切
everything is on the same port but we
一切都在同一个港口，但我们
can change the configuration
可以更改配置
configuration to tell spring boot to
告诉Spring Boot的配置
make the prometheus endpoint public that
公开普罗米修斯端点
should that should hopefully help so
应该应该帮助吗
right now
马上
Prometheus should be able to pull data
Prometheus应该能够提取数据
from our application and it should
从我们的应用程序，它应该
collect metrics this is very very slow
收集指标非常慢
so at least we've got something recorded
所以至少我们有记录
in our metric system of our one of our
在我们之一的公制中
incidents about the application being
有关应用程序的事件
slow so we might have a chance to see
慢，所以我们可能有机会看到
somewhere what caused it and what was
什么地方造成了什么，是什么
the impact so let's look at that
影响，让我们看一下
primitives for a minute so that you can
一分钟的原语，以便您可以
see actually the raw data and the letter
实际看到原始数据和字母
will we'll show you how you can
我们会告诉你如何
basically show that that data in a
基本上表明
dashboard so this is all the stuff that
仪表板，所以这就是
currently primitives recalls there's
目前原始人回想起
also some primitives specific metrics
还有一些原始的特定指标
that are not recorded by the Springwood
斯普林伍德没有记录的
application that all the rest is and
剩下的就是
something we would be interested in is
我们会感兴趣的是
to look at max time for server requests
查看服务器请求的最长时间
and one in particular which is
特别是
see this one which is our basically end
看到这是我们的基本目的
point we were we've been working on so
我们一直在努力
you can see all the tags being added so
您可以看到所有添加的标签，因此
the application tag there is also an
应用程序标签中还有一个
instance the name of the job the name of
实例作业名称
the job is the thing in the Yammer we
工作是Yammer中的事情
had and we can see that the max is
拥有，我们可以看到最大为
almost eight seconds rings a bell right
差不多八秒钟就按钟
the good thing with the tags that you
带有标签的好东西
don't have to get like very broad
不必变得非常广泛
metrics you can ask for a specific like
您可以要求特定指标的指标
give me the 90 percentile of get
给我百分之九十
requests on that path with like with a
与该路径类似的请求
HTTP status 200 so you can really like
HTTP状态200，因此您可以真正喜欢
drill down and see what's going on and
深入了解发生了什么，然后
and really know about is specific cases
真正知道的是具体情况
and and I'd have a clearer picture of
而且我会更清晰地了解
what's going on so by default we have
这是怎么回事，所以默认情况下，我们有
that dashboard so if you're getting
该仪表板，所以如果你得到
Ravana and getting the default backboard
Ravana和获取默认篮板
for spring dude so that's quite
对于春季花花公子，这是相当
interesting that you you basically get
有趣的是，你基本上得到了
that manage for you out of the box and
开箱即用，为您服务
you can add your own so let's have we've
您可以添加自己的，所以让我们
prepared a dashboard with a bit more
准备了更多的仪表板
data I need to take the right name here
数据，我需要在这里使用正确的名称
and then we can see the max but in this
然后我们可以看到最大值
case this is not the max for the server
如果这不是服务器的最大值
but it's the max for the HTTP client
但这是HTTP客户端的最大值
request the server is issuing so it's
请求服务器发布，因此
basically what we are doing with the web
基本上我们在网络上做什么
client and the key piece here is to
客户，这里的关键是
remember when we explain there is a
记得当我们解释有一个
restaurant editor and a web client
餐厅编辑器和网络客户端
builder that sort of configured by
由...配置的构建器
spring boot it's quite important to use
弹簧靴，使用非常重要
those bits if you're interested by a
这些位，如果您对
consistent developer experience yeah
一致的开发人员经验
we're not only configuring the message
我们不仅在配置消息
converters and codecs for Jackson and so
杰克逊等的转换器和编解码器
on but we're also instrumenting things
继续，但我们也在检测事物
on the fly so it's not it's not just
在飞，所以不是，不只是
about like the features you get from it
就像您从中获得的功能一样
it's about also the important DevOps
这也与重要的DevOps有关
stuff you can get out of it so the next
你可以摆脱的东西，所以下一个
time for those in the back and probably
那些在后面的人的时间，可能是
in the middle of the room the max for
在房间中间
the the free reverse lookup is 7.8
免费反向查询为7.8
second so we can now clearly see that
第二，所以我们现在可以清楚地看到
our free DNS lookup is the culprit so
我们的免费DNS查找是罪魁祸首，所以
that's the thing that we call to get the
这就是我们所谓的获取
name from the IP yeah so what can we do
是IP的名字，所以我们该怎么办
to to fix that because something we
解决这个问题，因为我们
didn't mention is that we actually in
没提到的是我们实际上在
this demo we have to reverse lookup
这个演示我们必须反向查找
there is a free one and there is one
有一个免费的，有一个
where we have to pay per call of course
当然，我们必须为每次通话付费
you don't want to call that if
你不想打电话给
everything isn't right but if you want
一切都不对，但是如果你想
to provide a decent user experience to
提供良好的用户体验
your users maybe at some point you you
您的用户也许在某个时候您
may have to fall back to the to the
可能必须回落到
custody option yeah so the easy solution
托管选项是的，所以很容易解决
in an imperative manner would be to go
势在必行
okay I'm going to go through the paying
好吧，我要去付款
version every time and this my Scott
版本每次，这是我的斯科特
this might cost you a lot of money but
这可能会花费您很多钱，但是
in here like Stefan said because we
就像Stefan所说的在这里，因为我们
control a bit the time and how things
控制一点时间和事情
are processed and how things evolve over
被处理以及事物如何演变
time we can do more fine-grain range
时间我们可以做更多的细粒度范围
things with with the way we're
与我们在一起的方式
collecting data so now that we have this
收集数据，现在我们有了这个
pipeline that we live where we basically
我们生活的管道基本上
zip those three things and we will have
压缩这三件事，我们将拥有
access to reactive operators we can very
使用反应式操作员，我们可以非常
easily improve that pipeline with
轻松改善该管道
something that doesn't know about HTTP
对HTTP不了解的东西
but can you can provide can provide you
但是你可以提供可以提供你
very interesting features for free so
免费的非常有趣的功能
what we want to do is back to this
我们想要做的就是回到这个
method there where we do the the free
在那里我们做免费的方法
reverse look-up on this publisher so it
反向查询此发布者，因此
at that point the operator itself
那时操作员本身
doesn't know about anything about the
一无所知
implementation right so it's a publisher
实施权，因此它是发布者
of a reverse route cab descriptor what
反向出租车的描述符是什么
we would like to do is we would like to
我们想做的是我们想
wrap it and say wait if I didn't hear
把它包起来，如果我听不到，请说等待
from you within let's say 500
比方说500
milliseconds just cancel give up and I
毫秒就取消放弃，我
will tell you what to do next and for
会告诉你下一步做什么
that there is a there is an operator in
在里面有一个运算符
project reactor code time-out probably
项目反应堆代码超时可能
need to use timeout you can give it
需要使用超时，你可以给它
there are several variants for for that
为此有几种变体
one including the simple one which gives
一个包括简单的给
you which where you give the duration
你给你持续时间的地方
the actual expected time out that you
您的实际预期超时时间
want to enforce and the backup solution
要执行和备份解决方案
so either a default value or you know
所以默认值或者你知道
case an alternate publisher something
案例备用发布者
else that will provide the the expected
否则将提供预期的
thing that we wanted to have in the
我们想要的东西
first place so here it's a concise and
首先，这是一个简洁明了的
nice way to say try the free version if
说免费试用版本的好方法
it doesn't work out in the amount of
它在数量上不可行
time that I've configured and just
我配置的时间
switch to the other one and the things
切换到另一个和东西
will go better and if we try and do that
会变得更好，如果我们尝试这样做
we kind of noticed that we don't have
我们有点注意到我们没有
the performance problem anymore but you
性能问题了，但是你
shouldn't trust us we should take a look
不应该相信我们，我们应该看看
at our dashboard to see what's going on
在我们的仪表板上查看发生了什么
so we need to wait a bit because the
所以我们需要等待一点，因为
scale went from 8 seconds to 500 right
比例从8秒增加到500
all right it's a little bit more traffic
好吧，这会带来更多流量
so what's expected here is that we'd
所以这里的期望是
like to see like the good cases where
喜欢看好情况
everything goes very well and the
一切进展顺利，
response time should be very low and
响应时间应该非常短，
we'd like to see the worst case scenario
我们希望看到最坏的情况
being like near or around the the
就像在附近
timeout that we've compared so that we
我们比较了超时时间，以便我们
don't really go over that time and the
真的不去那段时间，
experience doesn't suck for our users
体验不会吸引我们的用户
it's here in the bottom actually
它实际上在底部
somewhere I can't I can't see the
我看不到的地方
difference but oh yeah the three one
区别，但是哦，是的，三个
went to 122 milliseconds top Wow okay
达到了122毫秒顶部哇，好
I'm sure we can that's the wrong thing
我敢肯定，那是错的
so we can manage to get a bit more okay
这样我们可以设法多一点
so it's really um we're instrumenting a
所以真的是我们正在为
lot of things with web client risk
网络客户端风险的很多事情
template the MVC 3 MVC web flux
模板化MVC 3 MVC Web流量
frameworks and a lot of things again in
框架和很多东西
the spring gecko system so you can build
春天的壁虎系统，所以你可以建立
a lot of dashboards in and keep an eye
许多仪表板并保持关注
on on interesting things in your
在你的有趣的事情上
application and this is the difference
应用程序，这是区别
between like not knowing what's
就像不知道是什么
happening and having just the health
发生并且只有健康
indicator telling you that something
指示器告诉你一些事情
works and really knowing what's going on
工作，并且真正知道发生了什么
and having the tools to really tweak the
并拥有真正调整工具的工具
experience and know where you're
体验并知道你在哪里
spending your time and resources so
花时间和资源，所以
we've had more data now with the latency
我们现在有了更多的数据与延迟
thing and you can see now that the max
东西，你现在可以看到最大
is almost 300 milliseconds because
差不多是300毫秒，因为
everything that's above average which is
所有高于平均水平的
basically a no-go and below here we're
基本上不行，下面是
talking to you about tags we can also
与您讨论标签，我们也可以
tag and we can also create a dashboard
标签，我们还可以创建一个仪表板
for this phone to your eyes one on top
这款手机让您眼前一亮
of each other so this is the number of
彼此，所以这是
operations of the caste service in green
绿色种姓服务的运作
and the yellow one is the free I know it
黄色是免费的，我知道
color should probably reverse but
颜色可能应该反转，但是
whatever and you can see that as soon as
随便你就可以看到
you the the biggest the tolerance is so
你最大的宽容就是这样
if you if you accept maybe I don't know
如果你接受的话也许我不知道
to second stop then you'll see the cut
第二站，那么你会看到削减
the free service number of operation
免费服务号码
raising and the other way around so it's
提高和反之亦然
actually very easy to design those
其实很容易设计
dashboards with the existing
现有的仪表板
capabilities of micrometer provides all
千分尺的功能可提供所有功能
right so now we've sold our performance
对，所以现在我们已经卖掉了表演
problem in a way that wasn't obvious to
问题以不明显的方式
do with rest template if we had that
如果我们有休息模板
problem but we can do even more with web
问题，但我们可以通过网络做更多的事情
clients things that are even impossible
客户什至不可能的事情
to do with rest on plate actually
与实际休息有关
alright you want to show that or you
好吧，你想证明那个或者你
want to show the properties we have 10
要显示我们有10个属性
minutes properties try both yeah ok so
分钟属性尝试都可以，所以
very quickly you wanna show what do we
很快你想告诉我们
want to show you is nothing really
想告诉你真的什么都不是
related to performance but this is
与性能有关，但这是
something that we've seen many times
我们已经看过很多次了
even not being really aware of and
甚至没有真正意识到
showing you how you can basically design
向您展示如何进行基本设计
an configuration structure for your
您的配置结构
application keys application
应用程序密钥应用程序
configuration keys and we use the same
配置键，我们使用相同的
features that what we are using
我们正在使用的功能
internally in the spring routine so
内部在春季例行活动中
rather than hard coding that 500
而不是硬编码500
milliseconds there what I would like to
毫秒那里我想
do is to be able to expose a
要做的是能够暴露出
configuration key and basically be be
配置键，基本上是
able to reuse that without bothering
能够重用它而无需打扰
where that's coming from
这是从哪里来的
so how the value has been done basically
那么基本上如何完成价值
yeah and binding to an add value
是的，并绑定到附加值
attribute doesn't count as doing
属性不算做
something I don't do that
我不这样做
it's actually easier to do it with
实际上，这样做更容易
properties it's just a POJO and you test
属性只是一个POJO，您进行测试
its you don't have to mess up with the
它你不必弄乱
environment you can easily add rich
您可以轻松添加丰富的环境
types like duration and bind to it from
像持续时间这样的类型，并从
the environment you can get a per
您可以获得的环境
environment property with your
您的环境财产
application properties file you can even
您甚至可以使用应用程序属性文件
add validation rules on your properties
在您的媒体资源上添加验证规则
so that if you've got like complex keys
这样，如果您有复杂的键
that should look like a reg expert or
应该看起来像reg专家或
something you can you can add validation
您可以添加验证的内容
rules on it so it's really rich gives
规则，所以它真的很丰富
you documentation it gives you a you
您的文档，它给您一个
you're getting help from the IDE or
您正在从IDE获得帮助，或者
you're getting help from from Springwood
您可以从Springwood获得帮助
itself so it's really easy and usually
本身，所以真的很容易，通常
it's it's the best course of action so
这是最好的行动方案，所以
basically what we have now is a very
基本上我们现在所拥有的
very very simple properties type where
非常非常简单的属性类型，其中
we would basically asking spring do to
我们基本上会问春天
bind keys that start with dashboard so
绑定以仪表板开头的键
if you find a key called dashboard dot
如果找到称为仪表板点的键
timeout then it will basically call the
超时，那么它将基本上调用
setter with a value right
具有价值权利的二传手
it's versus or as a component now which
现在是vs还是作为组件
means it's a bin so I can I can go ahead
表示它是垃圾桶，我可以继续前进
with on my stats service where I have
在我的统计服务中
the value over here and replace that
在这里的价值，并取代
with this timeout which I need to inject
有这个超时，我需要注入
somewhere so let's do it here and since
某个地方，让我们在这里做，因为
in the code it's a regular component you
在代码中，它是常规组件
can inject it in the constructor of your
可以将其注入到您的构造函数中
of your service
您的服务
class and that'll work but the
类，这将工作，但
interesting thing is if you look at that
有趣的是，如果你看着那个
code that code doesn't know anything
该代码什么都不知道的代码
about how it was bound if it's something
关于它是如何绑定的
coming from the environment it's just a
来自环境，这只是一个
type of data structure that basically
基本上的数据结构类型
describes your configuration and this
描述您的配置
tribes also the the self.namespace or
部落也是self.namespace或
subgroups that your configuration may
您的配置可能包含的子组
have in this very simple case there's a
在这种非常简单的情况下，
single property but you can add like
单一属性，但您可以添加像
inner classes if you want to structure
内部类，如果你想结构
the keys a bit more but as a consumer of
钥匙多一点，但作为消费者
that object I don't need to care about
我不需要关心的那个对象
where that's coming from
这是从哪里来的
right so let me what did we say again
对，让我再说一遍
dashboard that timeout let's say four
仪表板的超时时间可以说是四个
seconds something like that not really
几秒钟这样的事情不是真的
helpful here let's try to be helpful
在这里有帮助，让我们尝试有所帮助
Auto completion in the ID oh yeah we
自动填写ID哦，是的，我们
don't have that but I just want to show
没有，但我只想展示
that actually it's taking more time now
实际上现在要花更多时间
there yeah there you go so okay we're
在那里，你走了，好吧，我们
back to a crappy situation which proved
回到糟糕的情况证明
that basically that works so let's move
基本上可以正常工作，所以让我们开始吧
it to a hundred milliseconds and that's
到一百毫秒
much faster error okay
错误快很多
so this is how you you can basically
所以你基本上可以这样
very easily exposed whiskey the problem
威士忌很容易暴露问题
is as Brian mentioned the idea is not so
正如Brian所说的那样
happy about it because it doesn't know
很高兴，因为它不知道
your key right so it can't basically
您的密钥正确，因此基本上不能
help you can't give you what the
帮助你不能给你什么
completion assistance it convoluted the
完成协助它使
value so you can you can put something
价值，因此您可以放一些东西
like this and the application for sure
像这样和应用程序肯定
won't restart if you do that so there's
如果这样做，将不会重启，因此
a very easy way to get the same user
获得相同用户的一种非常简单的方法
experience by adding an extra step to
通过增加一个额外的步骤来体验
your build which which is what we are
您的建筑，这就是我们
going to do now so if you add the
现在要这样做，如果您添加
required nice dependency which is an
需要良好的依赖关系
annotation processor when your
当您的注释处理器
application is being compiled it will
正在编译应用程序
create a metadata file in in with you
与您一起创建元数据文件
with your classes and this will be
与您的课程，这将是
picked up by your IDE and this will be
由您的IDE拾取，这将是
picked up by various tools so this this
被各种工具捡起，所以这个
is a just a JSON format that the
是一种JSON格式
Springwood team has defined and this
Springwood团队已经定义了
will be picked up by things including
会被包括
your favorite ID so you can get support
您最喜欢的ID，以便获得支持
and other completion in your ie default
和其他完成您的即默认
values documentation if there is
值文档（如果有）
validation it'll tell you something
验证它会告诉你一些事情
something goes wrong so yeah really
出问题了，是的，真的
helpful sad whatever alright so yeah
乐于助人的悲伤，好吧
let's go maybe with one more trick with
让我们一起去吧
the web client we have five minutes yeah
网络客户端，我们有五分钟的时间
so the thing you can the the thing you
所以你可以做的事
can do with what it's just way more than
可以做的不仅仅是
just a a synchronous collection it's
只是一个同步集合
actually a a stream of data you're
实际上是您的数据流
getting elements as they come so so far
到目前为止获取的元素
we've used it as an asynchronous list
我们已经将其用作异步列表
but here what we'd like to do is let's
但是在这里我们要做的是
say we have an endpoint on our service
说我们的服务有一个终点
where we are collecting the statistics
我们在哪里收集统计数据
and we have an endpoint where we can no
我们有一个终点，我们无法
real-time the number of projects that
实时的项目数量
are being created on start offering that
在开始提供时被创建
IO so the thing we'd like to have is
IO，所以我们想要拥有的是
have a dashboard that's a bit fancier
有一个有点幻想的仪表板
and collect that data in real time
并实时收集数据
should happen okay and then we can show
应该会发生，然后我们可以显示
how we make that happen okay yeah so
我们如何做到这一点好吧，所以
this is what's happening so right now
这就是现在发生的事情
the browser is connecting to our
浏览器正在连接到我们的
dashboard application through an SSC
通过SSC的仪表板应用程序
endpoint so server side events server
端点，因此服务器端事件服务器
sent events and if you look into your
发送事件，如果您调查您的
network ya network tab you can see the
网络ya网络标签，您可以看到
actual events being sent to your browser
实际事件发送到您的浏览器
but the trick is it's not polling done
但诀窍是还没有完成轮询
from the dashboard to the other remote
从仪表板到另一个遥控器
service it's an actual persistent
服务是一个实际的持久性
connection being shared amongst all the
在所有之间共享连接
the browser's looking at that dashboard
浏览器正在查看该仪表板
so you're getting the event and each
所以你得到的事件和每个
event is being broadcasted to all the
事件正在广播给所有
consumers and that data is being just
消费者，而数据只是
written to all the all the browser's and
写入所有浏览器的
listening to what's happening so it's
听发生的事情，所以
really efficient and it's not really
真的很有效，不是真的
requiring a lot of work or thoughts it's
需要很多工作或想法
just here's of vlogs and a spring MVC
只是这里的vlog和Spring MVC
knows how to deal with them in that
知道该如何对付他们
manner and it knows that a flux can be
方式，它知道通量可以是
written as a stream of data and it's
写成数据流，它是
written as a service an event stream
作为服务编写事件流
here so basically what we have is we
在这里，基本上我们拥有的是
have this back-end sending JSON 3 much
让这个后端多发送JSON 3
Brian just explained on the the main
布赖恩只是在主要解释
application the dashboard application
应用仪表板应用
we've added a new method that basically
我们添加了一种新方法
returned the flags so it doesn't do
返回了标志，所以它没有做
anything like just trimming whatever
像修剪任何东西
comes and there's an extra and the two
来了，有一个额外的和两个
extra operators added to that flux one
额外的运算符添加到该通量中
is share which will do the unique HTTP
是共享，它将执行唯一的HTTP
connection Brian just mentioned there's
布莱恩（Brian）刚才提到
also a cache operator so that if you
也是一个缓存运算符，如果
reset you basically get the last twenty
重置您基本上得到最后二十
items that we knew about that's
我们知道的项目是
basically when you refresh here we get
基本上，当您在这里刷新时，我们得到
the last twenty when you you're not
当你不在时的最后二十
starting over
重新来
this is stalled
这停滞了
so this publisher is stalled as a field
因此，该发布者被拖延为一个字段
so you're not creating that pipeline
所以你不创建那个管道
every now every time again because
每一次，每一次，因为
that's the purpose of the caching right
那就是缓存权的目的
so you have a definition and whoever is
所以你有一个定义，无论是谁
actually asking for it will get the same
实际要求将得到相同
publish for instance so this is what we
例如发布，这就是我们
return here which basically represents
返回这里基本上代表
the stream of data and the next step is
数据流，下一步是
to send that to the browser using sse
使用sse将其发送到浏览器
and it's as easy as just returning that
就像返回它一样简单
and with the proper media type so if we
并使用适当的媒体类型，如果我们
go to live stream on our back-end this
在我们的后端直播
is basically what the browser what the
基本上是什么浏览器
browser sees and then on the client side
浏览器看到然后在客户端
what you do is you create a new endpoint
您要做的是创建一个新端点
using the javascript api and just call
使用javascript API并调用
that so it's using servlet asing
所以它正在使用servlet asing
processing but it's not using async i/o
处理，但未使用异步I / O
so that's really the difference between
所以这真的是
doing that with MVC and that would bat
用MVC做到这一点，这将蝙蝠
flux with MVC you're dealing with things
与MVC交流，您正在处理事物
asynchronously it's just like adding at
异步地就像在添加
async on a controller method but you
在控制器方法上异步，但是你
still have to deal with one thread per
仍然必须每个处理一个线程
request and so on so it's it's still
要求等等，依旧
consuming more resources than doing the
消耗的资源比做
same thing with web hooks so that's the
与Web挂钩相同的东西是
difference but still functionally you
差异，但仍然在功能上
get the same feature for a user so
为用户获得相同的功能，因此
that's pretty much what it's show so
那几乎就是它所显示的
we've got one minute 40 seconds and
我们有一分钟40秒，
everybody wants to have lunch I'm sure
每个人都想吃午饭
yeah we're the last hurdle between you
是的，我们是你们之间的最后障碍
and before the line start for me
在我开始之前
it up alright alright thank you very
好了，很好，非常感谢
much enjoy the rest of the conference
非常喜欢会议的其余部分
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]